JONATHAN MBWARA

Address, UK 07480686788 jonny_mbuara@hotmail.co.uk

PROFESSIONAL SUMMARY

A highly motivated and well-qualified Law and criminology graduate. Through this I have managed to become well rounded in the following, legal operations, family law, commercial law, legal contracts, legal documentation. I also possess a sound knowledge regarding social and global issues, human and social behaviors, and the impact this has on public policy development. I have good knowledge of public policy and possess the ability to successfully interpret and assess the impact of policy on society.

I possess relevant professional experience gained throughout my education and employment. A very responsible and well-articulated young man with a wide range of skills and experience ranging from policy interpretation to personal employment advisor. I am a skillful writer with great verbal communication and the ability to read, write and speak in three languages. Rapport building comes as second nature to me, I can develop relationships both outside and inside my organization. For example, in my current role I still communicate and network with my old colleagues at DWP to better assist my participants.

AREAS OF EXPERTISE

- Legal Drafting	- Legal Bodies Affairs	- Criminal Law
- Consultative Sales Technique	- Sales Lead Generation	- Customer Service
- Family Law	- Talent Management	- Recruitment

ACADEMIC QUALIFICATIONS

Sep. 2016 - Jul. 2020	University of Northampton	Northampton, UK
	BA. Law and Criminology	
Sep. 2014 - Jul. 2016	Henley College	Coventry, UK
	Uniformed Services Level3: DDM	
Sep. 2008- Jul. 2013	Barrs Hill Community School	Coventry, UK
	GCSEs: - 9 A-C including Maths (C), English Language (C), English	
	literature (B), Science(C), French(A)	

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

Reed n Partnership Employment Advisor Sep.2020

- Attraction and Enlisting- Develoing and maintaining strong relationships with referal organisations such as Job
 centre Plus e.g. with JCP Business Manager and work coaches. May also include conducting outreach events
 and community organisations, attending job fairs and employer events. Occassionally would liaise with
 makreting team on content and design for marketing material.
- Engagement and Diagnostic- Planning on time for my appointment with participants is critical as I need to
 ensure effective use of my time, and also make sure my rapport building and level of two way exchange with
 my participant is adequate. I would use a number of forms to achieve this, such as participatn referal forms,
 initial assessment, assessment of readiness to work and change, health & well being assessment and so on. It's
 integral for me to identify barriers directly or indirectly whilst also identifying job prospects and goals.
- Participatant Progression- Progressing my participants would include the ability to sustain employment but
 also new job search skills, strategic thinking, confidence and empowerment. I follow this up with regular skills
 training, health & well being support. I also regulalry manage our Government financed spend also known as
 Personal Job Accounts in order to apply for necessary resources so participants can sustain employment..
 Examples of Participant personal job accounts include, bus passes, interview clothes, subsistence etc.
- Training Delivery- As well as providing 1-to-1 advice and guidance I am required to also facilitate and run training sessions. Training sessions involvesimparting information to learners in an interesting, engaging and empowering manner. It is vital my sessions meet the learners needs and learning styles, and the continuous reinfoorcements of learning outcomes and monitoring learners understanding/development through

- appropriate assessments.
- Employer Vacancy Development- Working for Reed n Partnership I would regularly sell the benefits of the companyd the programmes on offer. I also pitch the benefits of hiring a specific participant to an employer in order to achieve a placement. To achieve my goal, I am required to research individual employer asssessment process so I can prepare the candidate accordingly. A high level of relationship management with the employeras imperative, as I need to negotiate processes to ensure placement, follwing up with both employer and participant
- In Work support- My support continues to extend even once participant has landed a placement. I conduct risk assessment on my participant so I can identify the appropriate level of support required, I do this by using Red, Yellow and Green coding. I essentially continue on mentoring my participant throughout their time in placement.
- Administration and Quality- A lot of quality administration is required, I am responsible for ensuring accurate and timely recording and reviews for completion and completeness of all partiticpants. For example, managaing participant sensitive details and requiremtns through every intervention.
- Counselling and Advising

DWP(Department of Work and Pension)

Universal Credit Control officer Jun.2020

Sep.2020

- Providing excellent customer service in a telephony and/or face to face environment to a diverse range of working age customers and employers.
- Making decisions regarding benefit entitlement by examining the available facts.
- Assessing claims and dealing with enquiries via electronic means
- Supporting the Department's aim that digital will become the primary contact channel for all claimant services.
- Being part of a team responsible for creating and working in a service delivery environment to support the delivery of excellent customer service, quality and performance

TSYS/Nationwide

Customer Service Agent

Nov.

2019- Feb.2020

- Responded to customer inquiries via telephone, email, SMS and chat to provide problem resolution in accordance with the organizations service standards.
- Received and placed telephone calls which are predominantly routine, but often require deviation from standard screens, scripts and procedures.
- Maintained detailed and current knowledge of the company's/assigned client's products and services.
- Achieved key performance indicators (KPI'S) in line with service level agreement including quality standards.
- Analyzed customer service needs for communication to service and technical departments, when applicable.
- Arranged interviews with hiring manager accordingly.
- Managed and communicated with recruitment agencies, brief them on the positions, act as their point of contact for receiving resumes & feedback.

Cafcass (Children and Family Court Advisory and Support Service)

Iul. 2019 - Nov. 2019

- Advised clients on their legal matters.
- Networking with family Court advisors, solicitors, judges, children services, prison services, schools etc.
- Assisted barristers with case preparations for murder trials such as developed cross-examination skills, examined witness statements and improved client interviewing skills.
- Drafter legal letters such as client care letter and letter of advice.
- Performed research tasks on legal matters of the client.
- Effectively liaised with clients via emails and telephone, arranging meetings and chasing information.
- Summarized SU (service users) issues and finding relevant solution.

Vodafone UK

Legal Intern

Sales Advisor

Sep.

2018- Jan. 2019

- Offered customers technical assistant, product advise and product buying.
- Placed orders in a quick and efficient manner to ensure the store receives items on time.

- Managed customer's accounts, billing, and service issues.
- Recorded information into citizen advice database by adhering strict confidentiality and data protection rules.
- Scheduled and managed interviewing process alongside hiring manager; work with hiring manager, HR and support staff to coordinate interviews.
- Developed, cultivated, and managed relationships with hiring managers to provide service excellence and recruitment expertise.

Capita

Legal Intern Apr.

2016- Sep. 2016

- Proof checked of every correspondence.
- Liaised with courts and other governmental and third-party organizations.
- Dealt with PNC (Penalty Charge Notice) issues.
- Provided accurate and appropriate information in response to client's inquiries.
- Performed research tasks on the Organization's Adviser Guide database to determine the best possible steps for solving clients' problem.

OTHER EXPERIENCE

Langar Aid Aug.2018-Sep2018

Citizen Advise Bureau

Administrator/Advisor Oct.

2018- Dec. 2018

University of Northampton

Athletics Society Secretary Apr.

2018- Jul. 2019

KEY SKILLS AND COMPETENCIES

- Ability to persuade others
- Effective communicator when speaking to clients or colleagues and when dealing with written correspondence.
- Strong listening skills to give customers a sense that their questions or concerns will be dealt with immediately.
- Commitment to providing excellent customer service in all aspects
- Fine attention to detail where mistakes or other discrepancies are spotted.
- Highly professional, impeccable business ethics and a demonstrated ability to work with confidential information
- Strong knowledge of the area's networking groups and professional communities.
- Ability to handle highly sensitive confidential employee information with discretion and good judgment.
- Highly organized and ability to adapt quickly to changing priorities
- Learning aptitude
- Analytical and critical thinking
- · Coaching, mentoring and advising
- Great interpersonal skills
- Leadership
- Teamwork
- Technological adaptability
- Project planning

SKILLS

Computing Skills: MS Office- Excel, Word, PowerPoint, Access, SAP, Orion English (Fluent), French (Fluent) and Lingala (Fluent).